Carl Michael Lang Mobile: 07460442580

E-mail: carl.m.lang@gmail.com
Nationality: South African

Passports: South African, German

Profile: Currently I'm focused on web technologies PHP, MYSQL, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, CSS, HTML 5, CSS3, Responsive design, customised CMS sites, integrating online shop sites with third party payment api's, I've worked at a commercial web development level for 4 years, as web developer at technology publishing house ITWeb Ltd. and currently at Jamie Oliver Ltd. I also have 2 years freelance experience. **Technical strengths - current**: PHP, MYSQL, jQuery / Javascript, HTML5, CSS, SASS, understanding of OOP, source control, git. Problem solving.Personal qualities: Excellent ability to learn new technologies and efficient problem solving. Excellent communication skills / understanding user / client requirements. Diploma in Computer programming, as well as self-taught programming.

Personal recent website projects:

http://wedontneedmuch.org/somalia/ http://wedontneedmuch.org/carllang/

Work Experience

Company: Jamie Oliver Ltd.
Position: Web Developer
Dates: June 2013 – current

Duties

Front end / back end web development / maintenance

Developed the following one page 'Hubs':

Save with Jamie – cms / backend Money saving meals 2 – front end /cms

Win a foodie break competition – front end / cms

Friday Night Feasts hub - front end /cms

Hellmans Hub - front end / cms Woolworths - front end / cms Other projects completed:

Member recipes – ajax cms

Media-kit – ajax form

Voting page for Summer jam competition – ajax

Newsletters

Gained excellent experience in working with:

¡Query, AJAX,JSON,HTML5, CSS3,SASS, Wordpress,Boostrap 3

Responsive design, media queries / Javascript

Photoshop

Introduced to source control using GIT / with Sourcetree

Mailchimp

Work Experience

Company: ITWeb Limited (South Africa)

Position: Web Developer

Dates: September 2010 – April 2013

Duties

- PHP Web site development / maintenance / support, joomla sites, customising joomla components
- Creating Surveys using Joomla plugin BF Survey Pro ,
- Coding / updating reports in ASP Classic / HTML / CSS
- Creating mailshots.
- Updating / creating newsletters HTML CSS PHP
- Implemented 3rd party online payment script in ASP classic

Company: Self Employed Position: Web Developer

Dates: August 2008 – August 2010

Duties

- PHP MYSQL HMTL CSS Freelance web development,
- Creation of CMS customised per site.
- Cleanstart-Dermalogica Website high profile site -
- Additional work on a social network site, created a social network site but funding discontinued
- Create site from PSD
- Online Shop using 3rd party payment system SETCOM
- Working together with graphic designers

•

Portfolio

www.cleanstart-dermalogica.co.za

www.plastixportal.co.za www.plastinternational.co.za

www.quyn.co.za

Company: Bishopstrade (South Africa)

Position: Junior developer

Dates: 25 February 2002 – August 2008 (contract work)

Duties - Research and development

- Basic Java application development on Linux
- Installed Oracle 9i on Linux
- Installed Bishopstrade's Freight Forwarding Software
- Administrating Linux
- Development of J2ME mobile apps on Linux
- Coded EAA Pilots personal details record management application... connecting to Oracle 9i Database
- Re-code "Bar Code creator" application from C code to Java code
- Java programming, fmx (Oracle format type file) conversion program
- Store and Retrieve BLOB from Oracle 9i Database using Java methods and functions that are called from oracle procedures
- Java program to convert PCL5e file (HP print file) to PDF, using third party software including SwiftView and PDFlib
- Send Email message with attachments from Java stored procedure in Oracle9i database. The
 Oracle application would call this Java stored procedure to send reports and invoices, which are
 stored in PDF format. Using Oracle Enterprise Manager to store java program
- Send a SMS to a cell phone from Java stored procedure in Oracle9i database using Vodazone's service, testing on the Vodazone server. This was to test bulk messaging of sms including data from an Oracle 9i Database
- J2ME (Mobile Java apps) Mobile Java development: Researched, designed and developed 18 MIDlet's which are able to run on Java enabled cell phones MIDP1.0,MIDP 2.0
- Upgraded Java program to convert HP print file to PDF format using open source code... saved company cost of third party software licences Swiftview & PDFLib, and saved clients storage space of printed documents

Education

Qualification: Matric Certificate (South Africa)

Institute: Edenglen High School

Dates: 1995 - 1999

Subjects

English
Afrikaans
Mathematics
Physical Science
HG

Technical Drawing
 HG

Computer Science HG

Qualification: Certificate of Competence (PC Repairs & Maintenance)

Institute: Edenvale Recreational Centre

Dates: February 1999

Qualification: Comprehensive Programming Diploma (Dip.Comp.Prog)

Institute CTI – (Computer Training Institute Bedfordview)

Dates February 2000 – August 2001

Modules

Introduction to computers 2001

Data Processing Concepts

- Operating Systems 1 2001
- Object & Program Design
- Programming C++
- Oracle Relational Database Design
- Systems Analysis 2 2001
- Introduction to Oracle SQL & PL/SQL
- Develop Oracle PL/SQL Program Units

Achievements: 82% Total Average

References: Mr. Shaun De Caires, Instructor at CTI Bedfordview Telephone: +27 011 450 1963

References available on request.

Additional Skills: Proficient in Photoshop, MS Office, Paint.NET, FI Studio 10, Ableton live. expert at using google search.

Languages: English, German

Other Interests: Music production, sound design, guitar, jamming...